EVAN A. SMITH

206 Elm Street, Box 204133, New Haven, CT 06520 Cell: 978-761-8825 - evan.smith@yale.edu

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Engineering student with a broad technical design background interested in renewable energy systems and innovation.

SKILLS

Technical Design Experience CAD Experience (SolidWorks, Maya, VW) Independent Problem-Solving Programming Experience (Java, Python, C) Technical Team Leadership Data Collection and Analysis

WORK HISTORY

01/2017 to Current Media Technician

Yale Student Technology Collaborative - New Haven, CT

Provide media resources to library patrons, as well as assisting in multimedia education and other technical projects on campus.

05/2016 to 09/2016 Optical Engineering Intern

Acacia Communications - Maynard, MA

Debugged long-distance optical transmitters and test software. Assembled, calibrated, and tested equipment racks for use in running load and stress trials.

01/2016 to Current Tour Guide

Campus Sherpa

Gave personalized tours of Yale's Campus to prospective applicants. Provided followup application and interview advice and tutoring.

05/2014 to 09/2014 Lab Intern

Acacia Communications - Maynard, MA

Worked during high school to build test racks for use in international calibration. Trusted to work independently to assemble sets of equipment worth hundreds of thousands of dollars.

EXTRACURRICULARS

- Yale Dramatic Association, Yale Drama Coalition, and Yale Baroque Opera Project
- Worked on 14 theatrical productions in first year on campus, including technical leadership positions with professional designers and technicians in roles including Lighting Designer, Master Electrician, and Projections Designer.
 - Jonathan Edwards College Council
- Served as Secretary, worked to convert student feedback into concrete change in a residential college. Led efforts to improve facilities on campus.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Henry David Thoreau Scholar
 - Selected as one of MA's top environmentally-focused college students.
- National Merit and AP Scholar

EDUCATION

Current

Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Yale University - New Haven, CT (Cumulative GPA: 3.56 / 4.0)

- Energy Studies Multidisciplinary Academic Program Student
- Relevant Coursework Includes:
- Mechanical Design, Introduction to Computer Science, Discrete Mathematics, Introduction to Electronics, Data Structures, Energy Technology and Society, Applied Multivariable Calculus, University Physics